AARON WAGUESPACK

Fort Collins, Colorado Cell (561) 866-9439

EMAIL AARON_WAGUESPACK@HOTMAIL.COM

Financial Analyst / Project Manager/Web Developer/ MBA

Skilled finance professional with 13 years of experience in industry leading technology, telecom and service related companies looking to move into web development. Entire business cycle experience from: long range planning, annual operating plans to monthly forecasts and closings. Primary focus in financial, forecast, budget and income summary modeling as well as ERP system management and data management. Aptitudes include:

- Capital and OPEX budgeting and modeling
- Predictive financial modeling and Metric tracking
- Financial statement analysis
- Month End Closings
- Headcount and Commission Management
- Executive-level Quarterly & Year End presentation skills

Technical Skills: Microsoft Office, Advanced Excel, Adaptive, GP, Office Connect, MDS, Essbase, Hyperion, Oracle, SAP, Adaptive, Management Reporter, internal ERP financial systems, Salesforce.com, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3-4, Javascript, jQuery, Node JS, GIT, GitHub, SQL, MySQL, ExpressJS, MongoDB, PassportJS, NPM, DOM Manipulation, REST, Agile, Scrum

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Designed and created the budgeting templates for 150+ different retail sites over 28 states that took into account different business, regional and management needs.
- Created individualized budget, forecast and metric models in which each regional manager has
 direct control over their departments yet rolls into a consolidated business unit view for
 reporting requirements and system uploads.
- Corporate contact for 20+ new acquisitions on integration, finance and process related training.
- Created new models or managed the transfer of Acquisition processes to ADP models for all aspects of forecast, close, plan and reporting requirements.
- Completely reorganized the commission process allowing for compensation payments to be made within 30 days after month end, instead of the previous 2-3 month delay.
- Created a model to forecast local and international cash balances allowing a view into when transfers would be needed to cover expenditures, plus giving the ability to forecast and track the quarterly use of cash.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PINNACLE AGRICULTURE, LOVELAND COLORADO

2014-2018

Pinnacle Agriculture a first in class retail distribution start-up business with over \$1.5 billion in revenues. Started in 2013 and as of 2018 had 150+ sites in 28 states.

Financial Analyst – Corporate Reporting

- Heavily involved in creating the budgeting and quarterly forecast process for all 150+ sites, personally in charge of designing and creating the excel budget templates for the site managers that doubled as system upload files into the various ERP systems.
- Heavily involved in creating the capital expense approval and tracking process. Personally tracked capital expenses through their life cycle including reporting / auditing.
- Heavily involved in the design, creation and management of the corporate monthly and quarterly reporting for all sites and executive packages. Creation and maintenance of P&L's, variance, FTE, and metric reporting including miscellaneous ad hoc reporting.
- Heavily involved in ERP system management including of maintaining multiple reporting systems, data and report design and management.

AARON WAGUESPACK

Aaron_Waguespack@Hotmail.com Page 2

PINNACLE AGRICULTURE, LOVELAND COLORADO — (CONTINUED)
Financial Analyst — Site Analyst

- Originally hired to develop and align the North Regions FP&A practices and reporting.
 Became the main corporate point of contact with North, starting with 27 sites and growing to over 70 through acquisitions and corporate restructuring.
- In charge of integrating and training new acquisitions on corporate processes and reporting. Lead monthly "Lunch and Learn" training session on everything from reading P&Ls to site suggested topics on best practices on inventory counts.
- In charge of month end analysis for the 70+ sites of the North region. This includes revenue, expense, capital inventory variance analysis, GL entries and accruals.
- Helped create and track new acquisitions against monthly pro forma ROI estimates.

ADP - VIRTUALEDGE, FORT COLLINS COLORADO

2008-2013

Automatic Data Processing, Inc. (NYSE: ADP), with nearly \$9 billion in revenues and approximately 585,000 clients, is one of the world's largest providers of business outsourcing solutions.

Financial Analyst

- Aligned the acquisition VirtualEdge's accounting processes in line with ADP's practices.
 Including Forecast, Plan, Headcount tracking, GL maintenance and any and all reporting.
- Created and maintaining the monthly expense forecasts and the yearly plans, as well as tracking headcount salaries and bonuses for close to 200 associates.
- Collaborated with regional directors on individualized monthly metrics to insure continued accuracy of the forecast and aid in their decision making processes.
- Maintained sales backlog and created reports to aid sales in their monthly forecasts.
- In charge of balance sheet reconciliations, expense variance analysis, all month end general ledger entries and providing support data for month end division close call.
- Creating year end and quarterly presentations for use by GM during meetings with senior corporate management.

Airspan Networks Inc, Boca Raton, FL

2005-2007

A NASDAQ listed company headquartered in Boca Raton, FL, Airspan develops and markets telecommunication equipment to service providers and resellers worldwide.

Financial Analyst

- Calculating, forecasting and tracking sales and agents commissions along with issue resolution, and balance sheet accruals.
- Forecast and tracking quarterly and full year OPEX spending across the company, along with variance analysis and other ad hoc analysis.
- Tracking and forecasting bank balances as well as updating and maintaining the company's current US Sales & Use Taxes, as well as registering in new states and coordinating efforts with outside tax specialists and state tax authorities.
- Administrator for Salesforce.com, including working with Sales teams to develop trackable metrics, report building, and maintaining the integrity of the data.

EDUCATION

Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO
Masters of Business with an emphasis in Finance (MBA)

May, 2012

Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL Bachelors of Science in Finance & Marketing May, 2005